

**SUMMARY** 

imsyed42u@gmail.com \ 91-982 336 6765

Software Engineer with 1.5+ years of professional experience and 3+ years of freelancing experience. Expertise in front-end and back-end development, specializing in JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, and Docker. Known for strong problem-solving abilities, adaptability, and a quick learning curve.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Programming Language:** Java, C, C++, Python
- Frontend: JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Next.js 13, TypeScript, Tailwind-CSS, Material-UI
- Backend: Node.js, Express.js, and TypeScript
- Databases: MongoDB, MySql,
- DevOps and Automation: Kubernetes , Docker, Jenkins
- Others: Git, Agile, Gitlab,

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Software Engineer**

Feb 2023 – Ongoing

Techweaver Systems (Startup) (React.js, Node.js, Mongodb)

Hyderabad, India

- Integrated OAuth authentication providers with Firebase Authentication to enable users to sign in using their existing accounts from Google, Facebook, Led 5 successful projects update release cycles.
- Developed and implemented a new front-end architecture using React.js resulting in a 25% increase in page load speed and a 15% increase in user engagement.
- Implemented and maintained front-end web applications, resulting in a 20% reduction in page load speeds and conversion rates by utilizing modern web technologies such as React.js and best practices for user experience and accessibility.
- Developed 6 interactive front-end applications using the React.js library and Next.js, enhancing consumer experience by

## Freelance Java Developer

Oct 2021 – Jan 2023

Upwork (Core Java, Java EE, )

Remote

- Contributed to the development and maintenance of 6+ web applications using Java/J2EE technologies, resulting in a 30% increase in client satisfaction."
- Contributed to the development and maintenance of Java applications for diverse clients, including e-commerce platforms, content management systems, and financial applications.

### Freelance Front-End Developer

Dec 2019 - Aug 2021

Fiverrr (JavaScript, React.js, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap)

Remote

- Developed and deployed over 15 front-end websites, showcasing a keen eye for design and functionality
- Collaborated closely with clients to translate their vision into user-friendly interfaces, resulting in high satisfaction rates
- Implemented feedback from clients to continuously improve designs and meet project goals
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and optimized performance for all projects

## PROJECTS 📢

# Cache-Enabled-Multi-Threaded-Proxy

- Designed and implemented a high-performance, cache-enabled multi-threaded proxy serverin C, optimizing server performance with **socket programming**, and **efficient caching** mechanisms.
- Led design of high-performance C proxy server, optimizing concurrency with socket programming, caching, and multithreading.
- Implemented advanced caching for faster response times and scalability, boosting server performance.

## Disney+ Clone (7)

- Čreated a fully functional replica of the Disney+ streaming platform using React.js for the front end
- Utilized the Movie Database API to fetch and display movie and TV show data, implementing dynamic API routes for efficient data retrieval.

### Full Stack Airbnb Clone (7)

- Utilized MongoDB to manage and store user data, property listings, and booking information efficiently.
  Designed and implemented a robust backend using Node.js and Express.js to handle server-side logic, user authentication, and data management.

### **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | CGPA: 8.72

Aug. 2019 — Nov 2022

S.R.T.M.U

Nanded, India

Coursework: Java, Data Structure And Algorithm, Software Testing, Software Engineering, Object-Oriented Programming, Operating System, Relational Database Management System, SQL, Visual Basic, C++.

Area of Interest: Big Data, Web3, Distributed Systems, Cloud Computing